In this video, we're going to continue our discussion of top-down parsing algorithms
在本视频中，我们将继续讨论自上而下的解析算法
with another strategy called predictive parsing. So, predictive parsing is a lot
使用另一种称为预测性解析的策略。因此，预测性语法分析的工作量很大
like recursive descent. It's still a top-down parser. But the parser is able to
就像递归下降一样。它仍然是一个自上而下的解析器。但是解析器能够
predict which production to use. And it's never wrong. [inaudible] parser is always
预测要使用的产品。而且从来没有错过。[听不见]解析器总是
able to guess correctly which production will yield to, will lead to a successful
能够正确地猜测哪种生产将让位于哪一种生产，将会导致一次成功的
parse, if any production. Well, it lead to a successful parse. And it does have some
解析，如果有产品的话。嗯，它导致了一个成功的解析。而且它确实有一些
two ways; first of all it looks at the next few tokens, so it uses look-ahead to
两种方式；首先，它查看接下来的几个令牌，因此它使用前瞻性来
try to figure out which production should be used. So, based on what's coming up in
试着想清楚应该使用哪种产品。所以，根据即将发生的事情
the input string, but also it restricts the grammars. So this, this is only works
输入字符串，但也限制了语法。所以这，这是唯一有效的
for a restricted form of grammars. And there's, the advantage is that there's no
以获取受限形式的语法。还有，好处就是没有
back tracking involved and so the parser is completely deterministic if you were to
涉及回溯，因此解析器是完全确定的，如果您要这样做的话
try alternatives. The predictive parsers accept what are called the LLK grammars.
尝试其他选择。预测解析器接受所谓的LLK语法。
And this is a really cryptic name, and so let me explain it. The first L stands for
这是一个非常神秘的名字，让我来解释一下。第一个L代表
left-to-right scan. So that means we're starting at the left end of the input and
从左向右扫描。这意味着我们从输入的左端开始，
reading left to right. And in fact that's what we always do, so all the techniques
从左到右阅读。事实上，这就是我们一直在做的，所以所有的技术
that we looked at, look at will have an L in the first position. The second L stands
我们看过的，第一个位置会有一个L。第二个L代表
for a leftmost derivation. So we are constructing a leftmost derivation. That
用于最左边的派生。所以我们正在构造一个最左边的派生。那
means we're always working on the leftmost non-terminal in the parse tree. And K
这意味着我们总是处理解析树中最左边的非终结符。和K
here, stands for K tokens of look ahead. And in practice, while the theory is
在这里，代表展望未来的K个代币。在实践中，虽然理论上
developed for arbitrary 'k', in practice, 'k' is always equal to one. And so in
为任意的‘k’开发的，在实践中，‘k’总是等于1。所以在
fact, we'll only discuss the 'k's, 'k' equals to one, in these videos. To review,
事实上，在这些视频中，我们将只讨论‘k’，‘k’等于1。回顾一下，
in recursive descent parsing in each step, there may be many choices of production to
在每个步骤的递归下降解析中，可能有许多生成选择
use, and so we need to use backtracking to undo bad choices. In an LL-1 parser, in
使用，所以我们需要使用回溯来撤销错误的选择。在LL-1解析器中，
every step, there's only going to be one choice of productions, of possible
每一步，都只有一种可能的制作选择
production to use. And, and what does that mean? Well, it means that if I have an
要使用的产品。这是什么意思？嗯，这意味着如果我有一个
input string if I have a configuration of the parser where I have some terminal
如果我在某个终端上配置了解析器，则输入字符串
symbols omega and a non terminal a you know, possibly now followed by some other
符号omega和非终端a，现在可能后面跟着其他
stuff there could be terminals and nonterminals, but again a here is the
这里可以有终端和非终端，但这里也是
leftmost nonterminal. And, the next input. Is a token T Well then there is exactly
最左边的非终结符。然后，下一个输入。是一个记号T，那么正好有
one production A goes to alpha on input T. Okay, there's only one possible production
一个结果A在输入T上变为alpha。好的，只有一个可能的结果
that we can use. And any other production is guaranteed to be incorrect. Now it can
这是我们可以利用的。任何其他的作品都保证是不正确的。现在它可以了
be that, that even A goes to Alpha won't succeed. It could be that we will be in a
也就是说，即使A去阿尔法也不会成功。有可能我们会在一个
situation where there's no production we could use. But in [inaudible] parser,
没有我们可以使用的产品的情况。但是在[听不见的]解析器中，
there will always be at most one that we could use. So in this case we would chose
我们最多只能用一个。所以在这种情况下我们会选择
to rewrite the string to Omega Alpha Beta. Let's take a look at our favorite grammar,
将字符串重写为Omega Alpha Beta。让我们来看看我们最喜欢的语法，
the one we've been using for the last couple of videos. We can see an issue here
就是我们在上几个视频里用的那个。我们在这里可以看到一个问题
with using this grammar for a predictive parser. Take a look at the first two
将此语法用于预测性解析器。看一下前两个
productions for T. They both begin with N's. And so if I tell you that the next
T的作品都是以N开头的，所以如果我告诉你们下一个
terminal in the input stream as we're parsing along is an integer that doesn't
我们正在解析的输入流中的终端是一个整数，它不
really help you in trying to distinguish between these two productions in deciding,
真的能帮助你在决定的时候区分这两部作品，
deciding which one to use. So in fact with only one token of look ahead, I can't
决定使用哪一个。所以事实上，只有一个标志是向前看的，我不能
choose between these two productions. And that is not the only problem actually, so
在这两部作品中选择一部。实际上，这并不是唯一的问题，所以
we have a problem with T but the same problem exist with E. We can see that here
我们对T有问题，但对E也有同样的问题。我们可以在这里看到这一点
both production for E begin with the non-terminal T, and it is really clear
E的两个产生式都以非末尾T开头，这一点非常清楚
what we're to make of that because a T against a non-terminal terminal, so how we
我们应该怎么做，因为T对着一个非终端终端，那么我们如何
even do the prediction but the fact that they begin with the same thing suggest
甚至还做了预测，但事实是它们都是以同样的事情开始的，这一事实表明
that it's not going to be easy for us to predict which production to use based of
对于我们来说，要根据哪种产品来预测要使用哪种产品并不是一件容易的事
only a single token of look ahead. So what we need to do here is we need to change
只有一个标志，那就是向前看。所以我们需要在这里做的是我们需要改变
the grammar. This grammar is actually unacceptable for predictive parsing, or at
语法。这种语法对于预测性分析来说实际上是不可接受的，或者在
least for LL1 parsing. And we need to do something that's called left factoring the
至少用于LL1解析。我们需要做一些叫做“左因式分解”的事情
grammar. So the idea behind left factoring is to eliminate the common prefixes of
语法。因此，左因式分解背后的思想是消除
multiple productions for one non terminal. So that's a mouthful. Let's do an example.
一个非终端的多个产品。所以这真是一张大嘴巴。让我们举个例子。
Let's begin with the productions for E. And we can see, again, that E, that both
让我们从E的乘积开始，我们可以再次看到，E，两者
productions for E begin with the same, the same prefix. What we're going to do is
E的乘积以相同的、相同的前缀开头。我们要做的是
just factor out that common prefix into a single production. So we're going to have
只需将公共前缀分解到单个产品中即可。所以我们将会有
one production where E goes to T. And then we're going to have multiple suffixes. So
一个E转到T的结果，然后我们会有多个后缀。所以
let's introduce a new non terminal X that will handle the rest. So here, we have E
让我们介绍一个新的非终端X，它将处理睡觉。所以在这里，我们有E
goes to TX. So it says that everything that E produces begins with T, and that's
去德克萨斯州。所以它说E产生的所有东西都以T开头，那就是
consistent with these two productions. And now we have to write another production
与这两部作品一致。现在我们还得写另一部作品
for X that handles the rest. And what would that be? Well, one possibility is if
对于处理睡觉的X来说。那会是什么呢？嗯，一种可能性是如果
we're in this production, we need to have a Plus E and then in this production
我们在这部作品中，我们需要有一个加号E，然后在这部作品中
there's nothing. So that's easy to handle, right. One possibility for X as it goes to
什么都没有。所以这很容易处理，对吧。X的一种可能性是，当它到达
Plus E and the other possibility as it goes to Epsilon. And now you can see the
加上E和另一种可能性，因为它去了爱普西隆。现在你可以看到
general idea. We factor other common prefix, we have one production that deals
大概的想法。我们考虑其他共同的前缀，我们有一个产品，交易
with the prefix and then we write, and then we introduce a non terminal or the
使用前缀，然后我们编写，然后我们引入一个非终结符或
different suffixes. And then we just have, multiple productions, one for each
不同的后缀。然后我们只有多部作品，一部一部
possible suffix. And you can see what this is going to do. This is effectively going
可能的后缀。你可以看到这会有什么效果。这实际上是在进行
to delay the decision about which production we're using. So instead of
推迟我们使用哪种产品的决定。因此，与其这样做，不如说
having to decide immediately which production we're going to use for E. Here,
我们必须立即决定要对E使用哪种产品。在这里，
in this grammar, we wait until we've already seen the T, whatever is derived
在这个语法中，我们一直等到我们已经看到了T，不管是从哪个派生出来的
from the T. And then we have to decide whether the rest of the production is a
然后我们要决定这部作品的睡觉是不是
plus, E or the empty string. Let's do the other, set of productions. So we have tea
加上E或空字符串。我们来做另一套作品吧。所以我们有茶
goes to, and now the common prefix is int that we want to eliminate So we're going
转到，现在公共前缀是int，我们想要消除它，所以我们要
to have just one production that begins with int and then we'll have a new, a
只有一部以int开头的作品，然后我们就会有一个新的，一个
non-terminal to stand for the various possible suffixes. And now we also have
非末尾，代表各种可能的后缀。现在我们也有
another production that doesn't h ave anything to do with int, and so we'll just
另一部与int无关的作品，所以我们就
leave that one alone, that production just stays here. Because it already begins with
别管那个了，那部作品就留在这里。因为它已经开始于
something different we won't have any trouble predicting between these two
一些不同的东西，我们可以毫不费力地预测这两个
possible productions, these two possible productions. And now we have to write. The
可能的作品，这两个可能的作品。现在我们要写了。这个
productions for Y And again, we just take, the suffixes of the productions that we,
Y的乘积，再一次，我们只取乘积的后缀，
left factored and write them down as alternatives. So one is empty and the
左因数并将其记为备选方案。所以其中一个是空的，而
other one is times T. So we wind up with times T or epsilon.
另一个是时间T，所以我们最终得到了时间T或ε。